Guide to the Records of the Institute of African American Affairs RG.9.8
New York University Archives
- Series V. Administrative Files, 1979, 1986-2004; 1993-1999; 6 Linear Feet in 13 manuscript boxes and 1 half manuscript box.; 21.27 Gigabytes in 1,534 computer files.
  - Artist-in-Residence -- Miscellaneous, 1996-1997; cuid17372 (Box 83, Folder 21)
  - Thulani Davis and Lila Wallace -- Reader's Digest Writers Award, 1996-1999; cuid17373 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Artist-in-Residence -- Cassandra Wilson, 1998; cuid17374 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Film Screening-- African Film Festival, 1999; cuid17375 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Africana Studies Program Annual Planning Report for 2002-2003, cuid17376 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Lorna Simpson, 2002; cuid17377 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Biographies, 1998; cuid17378 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Reception Schedule -- Yari Yari, Black Women Writers..., 1995, 1997-1998; cuid17379 (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Africana Studies Celebration -- Book Signing, 1997-1999; cuid17380 (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - IAAA Events, 1997-1998; cuid17381 (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Habib Koité, 2001; cuid17382 (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Black Genius -- Book, 1999; cuid17383 (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Black Genius -- Miscellaneous, 1998; cuid17384 (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Black Genius -- Correspondence, 1997-1998; cuid17386 (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - Black Genius -- Miscellaneous, 1996-1999; cuid17387 (Box 58, Folder 14, Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Black Genius -- Biographies, 1995-1998; cuid17388 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Black Genius -- Miscellaneous, 1996-1997; cuid17389 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Black Genius -- Biographies, 1996-1997; cuid17390 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Black Genius -- Brochures and Flyers, 1996; cuid17391 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Black Genius -- Development and Funding, 1996-1997; cuid17392 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Black Genius -- Contracts for Appearances, 1996-1997; cuid17393 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Black Genius -- Spike Lee, 1996-1998; cuid17394 (Box 59, Folder 8, E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_20)
  - Black Genius -- Julianne Malveaux, 1996-1998; cuid17396 (Box 59, Folder 9, E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_17)
  - Black Genius -- Walter Mosley, 1997-1998; cuid17397 (Box 59, Folder 10, E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_22)
  - Black Genius -- Randall Robinson, 1997-1998; cuid17398 (Box 59, Folder 11, E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_19)
  - Black Genius -- Media, 1996-1997; cuid17400 (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - Black Genius -- Proposal, 1996; cuid17401 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Black Genius -- Speaker Photographs, 1996-1997; cuid17402 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Black Genius -- Nathan Cummings Foundation Funding Proposal, 1996-1997; cuid17403 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Black Genius -- Receptions, 1996-1997; cuid17404 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Black Genius -- Farai Chideya, 1997; cuid17405 (Box 60, Folder 5, E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_13)
  - Black Genius -- Stanley Crouch, 1996-1998; cuid17406 (Box 60, Folder 6, E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_21)
  - Black Genius -- George Curry, 1997-1998; cuid17407 (Box 60, Folder 7, E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_14)
  - Black Genius -- Angela Davis, 1997-1998; cuid17408 (Box 60, Folder 8, E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_10)
  - Black Genius -- Joycelyn Elders, 1996-1998; cuid17409 (Box 60, Folder 9, E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_16)
  - Black Genius --bell hooks, 1996-1997; cuid17410 (Box 60, Folder 10, E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_12)
  - Black Thought in Progress -- "Justice Clarence Thomas in Retrospect" -- A. Leon Higginbotham, 1995; cuid17411 (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Faculty Readings -- Printed Material, 1998; cuid17412 (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Faculty Reading -- Correspondence, 1998; cuid17413 (Box 60, Folder 13)
  - Faculty Reading -- Reception Menus, 1998; cuid17414 (Box 60, Folder 14)
  - Faculty Reading -- Invitation List, 1998; cuid17415 (Box 60, Folder 15)
  - Faculty Reading -- Invitations, 1998; cuid17416 (Box 60, Folder 16)
  - Yari Yari Black Women Writers and the Future Conference Material, 1997-10-15-1997-10-18; cuid18082 (Box 60, Folder 17)
  - Yari Yari: Black Women Writers and the Future Conference Video, 1997-10-15-1997-10-18; cuid17535 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_60)
  - Black Aesthetics Series, 2001; cuid17417 (Box 60, Folder 18)
  - Black Aesthetics -- Event Reports and Proposals, 2001-2002; cuid17494 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_7)
  - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Symposium Executive Summary, 1999; cuid17418 (Box 60, Folder 19)
  - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Symposium Funding Dinner Responses, 1999; cuid17419 (Box 60, Folder 20)
  - IAAA Event Press Releases, 1994-1995; cuid17420 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- New York Council for the Humanities Report, 2000-2001; cuid18083 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Trotter, Joe William -- Introduction from Black Migration in Historical Perspective, 1991; cuid17421 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Roberts, Dorothy -- Killing the Black Body, Chapter 4, 1997; cuid17422 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Said, Edward -- Orientalism, Introduction and Afterword, 1979; cuid17423 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Pascoe, Peggy -- "Gender Systems in Conflict: The Marriages of Mission-Educated Chinese American Women, 1847-1939" in Unequal Sisters, 1989; cuid17424 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Omi, Michael and Howard Winant Racial Formation in the US, 1986; cuid17425 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Symposium Press Releases, Invitations, Programs, 1999; cuid17426 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Symposium Fundraising, 1999; cuid17427 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Yari Yari Conference Programs and Publicity, 1997-2004; cuid17428 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Yari Yari Pamberi Conference -- Registration Lists and Correspondence, 2004-10-12-2004-10-16; cuid17527 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_52)
  - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Symposium Photographs, 1999; cuid17429 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Proposals, 1999; cuid17430 (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Dinner, Proposal, Invitees, 1999; cuid17431 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Symposium Travel Arrangements, 1999; cuid17432 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Press Lists and Travel Arrangements, 1999; cuid17433 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Symposium Speaker Information and Biographies, 1999; cuid17434 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Symposium Speaker Information and Biographies RESTRICTED, 1999; cuid18090 (Box 100, Folder 1-2)
  - Slave Routes: The Long Memory Symposium -- Program and Letter, 1999; cuid17526 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_50)
  - IAAA Events Press and Arrangements, 1999-2000; cuid18084 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Bamboozled Panel Discussion -- Publicity, 2000; cuid18085 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - France in Africa / Africa in France Lecture Series -- Flyers, 1998-1999; cuid17437 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Artist-in-Residence -- Miscellaneous, 1997-1998; cuid17438 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Event Calendars, 1998; cuid17439 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Walter Mosley -- Always Outnumbered, 1998; cuid17440 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Florence Project -- Conference at La Pietra, 1997-1998; cuid17441 (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Black Genius -- Programmatic, 1997-1998; cuid17442 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Black Genius -- Meetings, 1997-1998; cuid17443 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Black Genius -- Flyers and Brochures, Calendar, 1997-2000; cuid17445 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Reading -- Scenarios and Briefing, 1998; cuid17446 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Core Faculty Events, 1998; cuid17447 (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Faculty Biographies, 1996-1997; cuid17448 (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - Fanon Conference, 1996; cuid17449 (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Press Releases, 1996-1998; cuid17451 (Box 66, Folder 13)
  - France in Africa / Africa in France Lecture Series -- Maryse Conde, 1998; cuid17452 (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - France in Africa / Africa in France Lecture Series -- Henri Lopes, 1997-1998; cuid17453 (Box 66, Folder 15)
  - Thulani Davis -- Artist and Society Series, 1998-1999; cuid17454 (Box 66, Folder 16)
  - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Save the Date Material, 1999; cuid17455 (Box 66, Folder 17)
  - Artist-in-Residence -- Danny Glover -- Events, 1998-2000; cuid17456 (Box 66, Folder 18)
  - Slave Routes: The Long Memory -- Executive Summary, Program, 1999; cuid17457 (Box 66, Folder 19)
  - Thulani Davis -- Artist and Society Series, 1998-03-26; cuid17458 (Box 66, Folder 20)
  - Press Clippings, 1999; cuid17459 (Box 66, Folder 21)
  - Artist-in-Residence -- Danny Glover -- Actors Workshop, 1998-10-13; cuid17460 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Distinguished Scholar-in-Residence -- Wole Soyinka, 1998-1999; cuid17461 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Slave Routes -- Shango: Tales of the Orishas, 1999-03-26; cuid17462 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Projects -- End of the Year Report, 1998; cuid17463 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Projects -- The Many Colors of Hip Hop, 1998; cuid17464 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Malidoma Patrice Somé, Spring 1999; cuid17465 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - African Film Festival, 1999; cuid17466 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Career Day, 1993; cuid17467 (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Events -- Promotional Materials, 1993-1995; cuid17469 (Box 67, Folder 10-12)
  - Henry Louis Gates -- Biographical Material, 1993; cuid17470 (Box 67, Folder 13)
  - Modern Days Ancient Nights Film Festival, 1994; cuid17472 (Box 67, Folder 14)
  - Women's History Month Lecture: Dr. Betty Shabazz, 1993; cuid17473 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Black Thought in Progress Lecture Series -- Ali Mazrui, 1994-11-09; cuid17474 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Black Thought in Progress Lecture Series -- Quincy Troupe, 1995-03-08; cuid17475 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Black Cinema: A Celebration of Pan-African Film, 1994-03-22-1994-03-30; cuid17476 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Black Thought in Progress Lecture Series -- Patricia Hill Collins, 1995; cuid17477 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - African Art Symposium, 1995; cuid17478 (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Event Promotional Materials, 1995-1997; cuid17479 (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Black Thought in Progress Lecture Series, 1996-1997; cuid17480 (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Black Thought in Progress -- Angela Davis -- Press, 1993-1994; cuid17481 (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Press Clippings, 1994-1996; cuid17482 (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - Artist-in-Residence -- Walter Mosley -- Events, 1996-1997; cuid18087 (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Events -- Promotional Materials, 1998-2002; cuid17483 (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - Events -- Promotional Material, Programs, 2003-2018; cuid18086 (Box 99, Folder 1-12)
  - Haiti on Screen Film Festival, 2004; cuid17436 (Box 99, Folder 16)
  - Haiti on Screen -- Images, 2004-02-05; cuid17513 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_36)
  - Events -- Guest Book, 2002-2004; cuid18089 (Box 99, Folder 17)
  - Events -- Photographs, 1984-1985; cuid18088 (Box 63, Folder 1-2)
  - Events -- Images, circa 1995-2000; cuid18091 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Black Genius Events -- Images, 1997; cuid18092 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Bamboozled Panel Discussion and Other Events -- Images, 1999-2000; cuid18093 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Diaspora Conversations Documentary -- Danny Glover and Manthia Diawara Trip to Africa Images, circa 1999-2000; cuid18094 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Diaspora Conversations Documentary -- Tape Transcriptions, July 1999; cuid17507 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_30)
  - Unknown Events -- Images, 2001-2004, undated; cuid18095 (Box 63, Folder 7-10)
  - Aerosol Kingdom: Subway Painters of New York City -- Captions and Images, 2001-2002; cuid17488 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_1)
  - Africa: The Art of a Continent Exhibition -- Articles, 1997; cuid17489 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_2)
  - Africana Studies Program -- Contact and Mailing Lists, Program Requirements, and Course Offerings, 1995-2005; cuid17490 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_3)
  - Africana Studies Program -- Faculty and Resources, 1999-2001; cuid17491 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_4)
  - Aimé Césaire -- Images and Colloquium Schedule, 2003-2004; cuid17492 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_5)
  - American Dilemma Revisited -- Budgets, Proposals, Contact Lists, and Event Images, 2002-11-01-2002-11-02; cuid17493 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_6)
  - Black American Cinema Reconsidered -- Event Images, 2003-11-07-2003-11-08; cuid17495 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_8)
  - Black Genius -- Speeches, 1998-1999; cuid17496 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_9)
  - Black Genius -- Anna Deavere Smith, 1998; cuid17497 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_11)
  - Black Genius -- Haki Madhubuti, 1998; cuid17498 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_15)
  - Black Genius -- Melvin Van Peebles, 1998; cuid17499 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_18)
  - Black Graduate Studies Association -- Conference Information, Correspondence, and Contact Lists, 1995-1996; cuid17500 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_23)
  - Black Renaissance Noire -- Work Files, 1992-2004; cuid17503 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_26)
  - Black Renaissance Noire -- Back Up Disc Files, 1998-2004; cuid17504 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_27)
  - Black Renaissance Noire -- Pull Quotes, 1999; cuid17502 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_25)
  - Black Renaissance Noire -- Special American Dilemma Issue, 2003; cuid17505 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_28)
  - Black Renaissance Noire -- First Troupe Submissions, 2004; cuid17501 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_24)
  - Derek Walcott Residency Events -- Images, 2003-11-11-2003-11-20; cuid17506 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_29)
  - Emilio Cruz -- Drawing and Painting Images, July 2004; cuid17508 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_31)
  - Events -- Announcements, Flyers, and Images, 1995-2003; cuid17509 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_32)
  - Events -- Digital Proofs for Lowery Sims; Marley Barry Touré; Masking and Power; Oscar Micheaux, May-July 2003; cuid17510 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_33)
  - Events -- Digital Proofs for Richard Wright; Robin Kelly; Same Boats; and Daniel Dawson, 2003; cuid17511 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_34)
  - Haiti Bicentennial Project -- Promotional Flyer and Images, 2002-2003; cuid17512 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_35)
  - Halifu Osumare -- The Black Body Writings and Class Files, 1995-1998; cuid17514 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_37)
  - Howard French Book Signing -- Image, April 2004; cuid17515 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_38)
  - Hugh Masekela and Harry Belafonte Events -- Images, 2003-2004; cuid17516 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_39)
  - Hugh Masekela Book Signing -- Images, 2005-02-25; cuid17517 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_40)
  - Department Budget, Restructuring Proposal, and Related, 1998-2003; cuid17518 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_41)
  - Individuals and Groups -- Images, August 2004; cuid17519 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_42)
  - Jules Allen Opening Reception, 2003-10-10; cuid17520 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_43)
  - Khary Polk Work Files, 2004; cuid17521 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_44)
  - Loving Exhibition -- Images, March 2004; cuid17522 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_45)
  - Making Carnival -- Exhibition Documentation and Images, July 2003; cuid17523 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_46)
  - Ralph Ellison Book Signing -- Image, 2002-03-08; cuid17524 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_48)
  - Street Scene Images By Frank Stewart and Petra Richterova, June 2003; cuid17525 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_49)
  - Clyde Taylor Celebration -- Event Images and Promotional Material, 2008-09-19-2008-09-20; cuid17528 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_53)
  - Contact and Mailing Lists, 1997-2004; cuid17529 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_54)
  - Events -- Digital Proofs for Celebration for Dash and Barry; Kamau Braithwaite; Kellie Jones on Lorna; and Lowery Sims, 2003; cuid17530 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_55)
  - Artist-in-Residence -- William Greaves, 2007-03-29-2007-03-30; cuid17531 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_56)
  - Far Cry -- Jazz Music, undated; cuid17532 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_57)
  - Randy Weston -- Introduction and Second Movement, African Lady, undated; cuid17533 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_58)
  - Final City -- Movie, 2003; cuid17534 (E-records Electronic Records, E-records UA_RG_9-8_ER_59)
- Series VII: Archived Websites, June 2018-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued annually.
  Website for the Institute of African American Affairs. In circa 2019, the Center for Black Visual Culture was established at IAAA. The website contains staff biographies, information about the current scholars and artists in residence, event listings dating back to 2001, photographs and videos from their programming, and information about their publication Black Renaissance Noire (which ceased publication in 2018). In 2023, the URL changed and the website predominated focused on the Center for Black Visual Culture. The Center for Black Visual Culture at the Institute of African American Affairs is an institute for "scholarly and artistic inquiry into the understanding and exploration of images focusing on Black people globally with critical evaluation of images in multiple realms of culture, including how various archives and the development of visual technologies affect the construction of representations."
  Appraisal
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored.
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.